Register of the Alfred M. Lilienthal papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1938-1995 (Boxes 31-68, 152-153)
  - "Where Goes the Middle East?" Speech, Rotary Club, Nantucket, Massachusetts. Press release and correspondence, 9 August 1955. (Box-folder 38: 42)
  - "What Price Elections!" Human Events, Printed copy, 10 September 1955. (Box-folder 38: 43)
  - Letter to the editor, Time, (date written). Carbon copy and response of the assistant to the publisher, Frank R. Shea, 26 September 1955 (Box-folder 38: 44)
  - Press release, Carbon copy, 19 October 1955. (Box-folder 38: 45)
  - Speech, National Federation of Syrian-Lebanese Clubs, Asbury Park, New Jersey, Press release, 23 October 1955. (Box-folder 38: 46)
  - "Should the United States Arm Israel?" Radio debate with Congressman Emanuel Celler (broadcast over WGTH) and two speeches: "The realities of the Middle East" and "Arabs, Israelis and American foreign policy," Hartford, Connecticut. Press releases and clippings, and listeners' reactions, 27 October 1955. (Box-folder 38: 47)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Herald Tribune, (date written). Carbon copy, 7 November 1955 (Box-folder 38: 48)
  - Letter to the editor, Providence Journal, Printed copy, 25 November 1955. (Box-folder 38: 49)
  - Press conference, Press release, 1956. (Box-folder 38: 50)
  - "Middle East: Friend or Foe?" Speech, Allegheny County League of Women Voters, Carnegie Music Hall, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Press release and clipping, 13 January 1956. (Box-folder 38: 51)
  - Participation, The Allegheny Roundtable, KDKA Radio, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, Letter from John C. Weaver, 22 January 1956. (Box-folder 152: 51)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, Printed copy, 29 February 1956. (Box-folder 38: 52)
  - Speech, Stamford Women's Club, Stamford, Connecticut, Press release, 7 March 1956. (Box-folder 38: 53)
  - "What Price U.S. Middle East Policy?" Speech, First Congregational Church, Los Angeles, California. Carbon copy of review by Herb Brin, 3 April 1956. (Box-folder 38: 54)
  - Speech, Los Angeles Breakfast Club, Los Angeles, California, (broadcast over KPOL). Printed copy and clipping, 4 April 1956 (Box-folder 38: 55)
  - Press conference, San Francisco, California, Clippings, 9 April 1956. (Box-folder 38: 56)
  - Letter to the editor, World Telegram, Printed copy and reactions of readers to AML's letter, 2 May 1956, 25 April 1956. (Box-folder 38: 57)
  - Debate with Congressman Emanuel Celler, Dumont television program "Between the Lines," Press releases; and typescript transcript of conversation with Charlotte Armstrong and her letter to AML, 6 May 1956. (Box-folder 38: 58)
  - Conversation with Herbert C. Hoover, Typescript account, 16 May 1956. (Box-folder 38: 59)
  - Press release, Carbon copy, 18 May 1956. (Box-folder 38: 60)
  - Letter to the editor, Long Island Daily Press, (date written). Carbon copy, and correspondence with managing editor Edward Gottlieb, 16 July 1956 (Box-folder 38: 61)
  - Press release, Mimeographed copy, 17 July 1956. (Box-folder 38: 62)
  - Statement on the Suez Canal, Mimeographed copy, 29 July 1956. (Box-folder 38: 63)
  - Press conference, New York City, Press release, 30 July 1956. (Box-folder 38: 64)
  - "Peace for Palestine," The Sign, Printed copy, August 1956. (Box-folder 39: 1)
  - Open letter to Karl S. Twitchell, Mimeographed copy, 1 August 1956. (Box-folder 39: 2)
  - Convention diary, Printed and typescript copies, and handwritten notes, 4-24 August 1956. (Box-folder 39: 3)
  - Statement submitted to the Platform and Resolutions Committee of the Democratic National Convention, Mimeographed copy, 7 August 1956. (Box-folder 39: 4)
  - Press conference, San Francisco, California, Press release, 13 August 1956. (Box-folder 39: 5)
  - Statement submitted to the Resolutions Committee of the Republican National Convention, Mimeographed copy, 16 August 1956. (Box-folder 39: 6)
  - Open telegram to the delegates of the Republican National Convention, Typescript, 21 August 1956. (Box-folder 39: 7)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, (date written). Carbon copy, 10 September 1956 (Box-folder 39: 8)
  - Statement issued at an emergency meeting of the Executive Committee of the National Committee for Security and Justice in the Middle East, Press release, October 1956. (Box-folder 39: 9)
  - Memorandum to the United States representatives on the Security Council of the United Nations, Mimeographed copy, 7 October 1956. (Box-folder 39: 10)
  - Press release, Carbon copies of two different versions, 8 October 1956. (Box-folder 39: 11)
  - "Arabs, Israelis, and Suez," Speech, Rotary Club, Hotel Commodore, New York City. Mimeographed copy, 1 November 1956. (Box-folder 39: 12)
  - Press release, Carbon copy, 1 December 1956. (Box-folder 39: 13)
  - Press conference, Semiramis Hotel, Cairo, Egypt, Press release, 6 December 1956. (Box-folder 39: 14)
  - There Goes the Middle East. See also card file box 146 for readers' reactions
    - 1957
      - Comments (Box-folder 39: 15)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 39: 16-22)
      - Mailing lists (Box-folder 40: 1)
      - Orders (Box-folder 40: 2)
      - Publicity material (Box-folder 40: 3)
      - Reviews (Box-folder 40: 4)
    - 1960
      - General (Box-folder 40: 5)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 40: 6)
  - "Arms, U.S. Policy, and Zionist Pressure," Speech, Propeller Club, Hotel Capitole, Beirut, Lebanon. Clippings, 7 January 1957. (Box-folder 40: 7)
  - Speech, Chicago Council on Foreign Relations, Chicago, Illinois, Press release, 14 January 1957. (Box-folder 40: 8)
  - Press conference, New York City, Mimeographed copy, 24 January 1957. (Box-folder 40: 9)
  - Statement on King Saud's visit to New York City, Mimeographed copy, 29 January 1957. (Box-folder 40: 10)
  - Testimony before the Senate Foreign Relations and Armed Services Committees, Washington, D.C., on President Dwight D. Eisenhower's Middle East program as delivered before a joint special session of Congress on January 5, 1957 (included). Mimeographed copy, 4 February 1957 (Box-folder 40: 11)
  - Press release, Mimeographed copy, 18 February 1957. (Box-folder 40: 12)
  - Press release, Mimeographed copy, c. March 1957. (Box-folder 40: 13)
  - Remarks as moderator, Middle East seminar, Intercollegiate Conference, Barnard College, Columbia University, New York, Clipping, 9 March 1957. (Box-folder 40: 14)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, (date written). Carbon copy, 22 April 1957 (Box-folder 40: 15)
  - "Those Myths about the Middle East," American Mercury, Printed copy, May 1957. (Box-folder 40: 16)
  - Press release, Mimeographed copy, 15 May 1957. (Box-folder 40: 17)
  - Radio appearance, Barry Gray Show, 15 May 1957. Press releases and correspondence with Rabbi William F. Rosenblum, as well as correspondence between William F. Rosenblum and Barry Gray. Includes correspondence with Aaron Sapiro and Eugene B. Block, editor of the Jewish Community Bulletin (Box-folder 40: 18)
  - "There Goes the Middle East," Speech, American Friends of the Middle East headquarters, New York City. Press release, 28 May 1957. (Box-folder 40: 19)
  - Radio appearance, Nightbeat, New York City, Mimeographed announcement and correspondence, 11 June 1957. (Box-folder 40: 20)
  - Radio appearance, Tex and Jinx Show, Peacock Alley, Waldorf Astoria Hotel, New York City, Typescript account of programming, 13 June 1957. (Box-folder 40: 21)
  - "What Do We Do about the Middle East?" Speech, Syrian-Lebanese Federation of Eastern States, Henry Hudson Hotel, New York City. Press release, 23 June 1957. (Box-folder 40: 22)
  - Press conference, Bellevue Hotel, San Francisco, California, Press release, 11 September 1957. (Box-folder 40: 23)
  - "Bookburning 1957," Speech, Young Men's Christian Association of the City of New York, William Sloane House, New York City. Correspondence, 3 October 1957. (Box-folder 40: 24)
  - Letter to the editor, Jewish Community Bulletin, Printed copy, 4 October 1957. (Box-folder 40: 25)
  - Open letter to the National Association of Syrian-Lebanese Clubs, Printed copy, 25 October 1957. (Box-folder 40: 26)
  - "There Goes the Middle East," Speech, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York. Correspondence and press release, 31 October 1957. (Box-folder 40: 27)
  - "Where Goes the Middle East?" Speech, American University, Washington, D.C. Correspondence, 18 November 1957. (Box-folder 41: 1)
  - "Where Goes the Middle East?" Speech, Wayne State University, Detroit, Michigan. Correspondence, 20 November 1957. (Box-folder 41: 2)
  - "Where Goes the Middle East?" Speech, Wabash College, Crawfordsville, Indiana. Correspondence, 21 November 1957. (Box-folder 41: 3)
  - "How the U.S. Can Promote Peace in the Middle East?" Speech, University of Missouri, Columbia, Missouri. Correspondence, 25 November 1957. (Box-folder 41: 4)
  - "Middle East 'Peace with Justice Plan'," 29 November 1957. Mimeographed copy. Includes correspondence and a first draft entitled "Middle East Peace Proposals," which was to be submitted to Secretary-General Dag Hammarskjold and was first distributed as an enclosure to a circular letter of 17 October 1957 to the members of the National Committee for Security and Justice in the Middle East. Includes also two internal memoranda at the Daily Pantagraph regarding AML and editorial policy (Box-folder 41: 5)
  - "Where Goes the Middle East?" Speech, Rollins College, Winter Park, Florida. Correspondence, 2 December 1957. (Box-folder 41: 6)
  - "Where Goes the Middle East?" Speech, Emory University, Georgia. Correspondence, 3 December 1957. (Box-folder 41: 7)
  - "Middle East: Friend or Foe," Speech, University of South Carolina, Columbia, South Carolina. Carbon copy of excerpts and correspondence, 5 December 1957. (Box-folder 41: 8)
  - "Where Goes the Middle East?" Speech, University of California at Berkeley. Correspondence, 6 December 1957. (Box-folder 41: 9)
  - "Where Goes the Middle East?" Speech, Merced County Republican Women's Club, Merced, California. Correspondence with Lorena Sischo, 9 December 1957. (Box-folder 41: 10)
  - "Where Goes the Middle East?" Speech, Mills College, Oakland, California. Correspondence, 10 December 1957. (Box-folder 41: 11)
  - "The Middle East: Friend or Foe?" Speech, First Baptist Church, Burlingame, California. Correspondence, 11 December 1957. (Box-folder 41: 12)
  - "The Middle East: Friend or Foe?" Speech, Claremont Graduate College, Claremont, California. Correspondence, 12 December 1957. (Box-folder 41: 13)
  - "Crisis in the Middle East," Speech, Arabian Club of San Francisco, San Francisco, California. Mimeographed copy, 13 December 1957. (Box-folder 41: 14)
  - "The J-I-L Plan: A Suggestion for the Middle East," Carbon copy, 1958. (Box-folder 41: 15)
  - Press release, Carbon copy, 27 January 1958. (Box-folder 41: 16)
  - "There Goes the Middle East," Speech, Brooklyn Woman's Club, Towers Hotel, Brooklyn, New York. Handwritten notes, 3 February 1958. (Box-folder 41: 17)
  - Series of articles on the Middle East for the Arizona Daily Star and the Nashville Banner, Printed copies, April-August 1958. (Box-folder 41: 18)
  - Press conference, Beirut, Lebanon, Carbon copy, 1 April 1958. (Box-folder 41: 19)
  - Statement, New York City, Clipping, 28 June 1958. (Box-folder 41: 20)
  - Article on the need for a new Middle East policy, Carbon copy, c. July 1958. (Box-folder 41: 21)
  - Outline of an article on Gamal Abdel Nasser, as described in a letter to Charles W. Ferguson, Reader's Digest, Carbon copy, 14 July 1958. (Box-folder 41: 22)
  - Statement issued to UPI, New York City, Mimeographed copy, 16 July 1958. (Box-folder 41: 23)
  - "To the American People," 29 July 1958. Carbon copies and reprint from the Congressional Record of, 20 August 1958 (Box-folder 41: 24)
  - Interview, "Mike Wallace Asks," Carbon copy, c. July-August 1958. (Box-folder 41: 25)
  - "A Visit with Prince Mashhur: A Story with Pictures," Typescript and carbon copy. Includes correspondence, c. August 1958. (Box-folder 41: 26)
  - Press release, Mimeographed copy, September 1958. (Box-folder 41: 27)
  - Review of Wilton Wynn, Nasser of Egypt, Carbon copy, c. 1959. (Box-folder 41: 28)
  - "The Balfour Declaration: Forty Years Later," 1959. Reprint from Issues and Conflicts, George Anderson ed., University of Kansas Press (374 pp., Includes mimeographed copies, handwritten notes, research material, and correspondence with George Anderson (Box-folder 41: 29)
  - "Book Burning: Fashion," 1959. Typescript (Box-folder 41: 30)
  - "The Turbulent Middle East," Film lecture, YMCA, Coatesville, Pennsylvania, 13 March 1959.
    - Commentary (Box-folder 41: 31)
    - Comments and reviews, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 42: 1)
    - Contract (Box-folder 42: 2)
    - Correspondence, 1958-1967 (Box-folder 42: 3)
    - Flyers, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 42: 4)
    - Notes (including those for a never-completed film on Jordan) (Box-folder 42: 5)
  - "The Turbulent Middle East," Film lecture, Brown Engineers International, New York City. Correspondence, 29 December 1959. (Box-folder 42: 6)
  - Series of articles on the Middle East for the Arizona Daily Star, Printed and carbon copies, February-April 1960. (Box-folder 42: 7)
  - "The Turbulent Middle East," Film lecture, University of Oklahoma, Norman, Oklahoma. Correspondence, 25 March 1960. (Box-folder 42: 8)
  - "The Turbulent Middle East," Film lecture, Town Hall, New York City. Clipping and correspondence with George Stoddard and others, 31 March 1960. (Box-folder 42: 9)
  - "The Turbulent Middle East," Film lecture, Jersey State College, Jersey City, New Jersey. Correspondence, 28 July 1960. (Box-folder 42: 10)
  - Press release, Typescript, September 1960. (Box-folder 42: 11)
  - "Kennedy, Nixon and the Middle East," Middle East Forum, Printed copy, November 1960. (Box-folder 42: 12)
  - Film on Kuwait, Budget estimates and correspondence, c. 1961. (Box-folder 42: 13)
  - "Are Arabs Right?" 9 January 1961. Speech, Knights of Columbus, Hotel Hollenden, Cleveland, Ohio. Letter to the editor of the Cleveland Plain Dealer, commenting on letters to the editor by others regarding his speech, and ensuing correspondence with readers. See also CORRESPONDENCE, Irwin, Josephine; Salem, Sam, 22 March 1961 (Box-folder 42: 14)
  - "Peace and Justice for the Middle East," Typescript draft and mimeographed copy. Includes correspondence, February 1961. (Box-folder 42: 15)
  - "The Turbulent Middle East," Film lecture, Spokesman Review Charities, Spokane, Washington. Clippings and correspondence, 9 February 1961. (Box-folder 42: 16)
  - "A New Approach to the Middle East," Speech, Canadian Friends of the Middle East, London, Ontario. Clippings and correspondence with Tom Cunningham, 26 April 1961. (Box-folder 42: 17)
  - "Where Goes the Middle East?" Speech, St. George's Orthodox Church, Houston, Texas. Correspondence with Thomas Skaff, 28 April 1961. (Box-folder 42: 18)
  - "The Turbulent Middle East," Film lecture, St. Thomas University, Houston, Texas. Press release and correspondence with Marguerite J. Barnes and Mrs. John O'Hare, 14 May 1961. (Box-folder 42: 19)
  - "World's Most Unusual Hospital," The Rotarian, Typescript draft and printed copy, September 1961. (Box-folder 42: 20)
  - "The Turbulent Middle East," Film lecture, Marines Memorial Theater, San Francisco, California. Notes, correspondence, and clippings, 5 December 1961. (Box-folder 42: 21)
  - Speech, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, California, Correspondence, 8 December 1961. (Box-folder 42: 22)
  - Speech, First Baptist Church, Burlingame, California, Correspondence with Cecil G. Osborne, 12 December 1961. (Box-folder 42: 23)
  - Letter to the editor, National Jewish Post, Printed copy, 9 February 1962. (Box-folder 42: 24)
  - "Still, What Price Israel?" Speech, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York. Press release, clippings, and correspondence, 7 May 1962. (Box-folder 42: 25)
  - "The Turbulent Middle East," Film lecture, Proctor Academy, Concord, New Hampshire. Correspondence, 23 October 1962. (Box-folder 42: 26)
  - "The Turbulent Middle East," Film lecture, City Auditorium, Concord, New Hampshire. Clipping, 24 October 1962. (Box-folder 42: 27)
  - Book on Kuwait, See also CORRESPONDENCE, Abdul Aziz al-Massaeed, c. 1963.
    - Typescript outline and correspondence (Box-folder 42: 28)
    - Research notes and material (Box-folder 42: 29)
  - "Big Shoes for Little Men," 1963. Carbon copy of outline for an unpublished book, and correspondence with several publishers, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 43: 1)
  - "Prologue (Epilogue): The Parable of the Goys and the Kikes," Typescript and carbon copies, 1963. (Box-folder 43: 2)
  - Letter to the editor, Lebanese-American Journal, (date written). Carbon copy, 29 January 1963 (Box-folder 43: 3)
  - "The New Middle East," Speech, American-Arab Association for Commerce and Industry, Waldorf-Astoria, New York City. Typescript, 27 May 1963. (Box-folder 43: 4)
  - "Arabia, Israel, Oil and Trouble," Speech, Rotary Club, Nantucket, Massachusetts. Typescript and carbon copy, 17 July 1963. (Box-folder 43: 5)
  - Open letter to Arthur Ochs Sulzberger, (date written). Mimeographed copy and press release of 16 December 1963, 13 December 1963 (Box-folder 43: 6)
  - Letter to the editor, New Statesman, (date written). Carbon copy, 20 December 1963 (Box-folder 43: 7)
  - Review of David Ben-Gurion, Israel: Years of Challenge, Carbon copy, c. 1964. (Box-folder 43: 8)
  - Review of Hannah Arendt, Eichmann in Jerusalem, Carbon copy and handwritten draft, 1964. (Box-folder 43: 9)
  - Letter to the editor, Washington Evening Star, Printed copy, 29 January 1964. (Box-folder 43: 10)
  - "The Middle East: Friend or Foe?" Speech, University of Bridgeport, Bridgeport, Connecticut. Correspondence and clipping, 4 March 1964. (Box-folder 43: 11)
  - Speech, American Management Association, general management briefing session on investing and operating in the Middle East and North Africa, New York City, Carbon copy, 20 July 1964. (Box-folder 43: 12)
  - Press release condemning the film Johnny Goldfarb, Please Come Home, Carbon copy and correspondence, 9 December 1964. (Box-folder 43: 13)
  - The Other Side of the Coin, See also card file box 146 for readers' responses and CORRESPONDENCE, American Friends of the Middle East, 1965.
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 43: 14-20)
    - Draft (partial) (Box-folder 44: 1)
    - Galleys (Box-folder 44: 2)
    - Mailing list (Box-folder 44: 3)
    - Opinions of Elmer Berger and Edward W. Overton, Jr. as expressed to Devin A. Garrity, and AML's reaction (Box-folder 44: 4)
    - Orders (Box-folder 44: 5)
    - Publicity material (Box-folder 44: 6)
    - Reviews (Box-folder 44: 7)
  - Press release, Mimeographed copy, c. March 1965. (Box-folder 44: 8)
  - Radio appearance, John Nebel Show, WNBC Radio, New York City, Press release, 11 April 1965. (Box-folder 44: 9)
  - Speech, American Whig-Cliosophic Society, Princeton University, Princeton, New Jersey, Correspondence with Roger W. Jones, Jr., 29 April 1965. (Box-folder 44: 10)
  - Interview, The Daily Star, Beirut, Lebanon, Printed copy, 27-28 June 1965. (Box-folder 44: 11)
  - Press conference, Cornell Club, New York City, Press release, c. July-August 1965. (Box-folder 44: 12)
  - Radio appearance, Night Talk, WCAU Radio, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, Program outline and letter of M. T. Mehdi, 16 September 1965. (Box-folder 44: 13)
  - "Land of What Free, Home of What Brave?" Speech, Yale University, New Haven, Connecticut. Correspondence, press release, and clipping, 21 October 1965. (Box-folder 44: 14)
  - "Let's Bury Hitler: The Road to Middle East Peace," Speech, American Whig-Cliosophic Society, Princeton University, Princeton, New Jersey. Handwritten notes, correspondence, press releases, and clippings, 18 November 1965. (Box-folder 44: 15)
  - "The Middle East: Another Vietnam?" Speech, Columbia University, New York City. Press release, 13 May 1966. (Box-folder 44: 16)
  - Statement on the cancellation by Mayor John Lindsay of the dinner for King Faisal, Mimeographed copy, June-July 1966. (Box-folder 44: 17)
  - "Opening Thoughts on First Visit to Vienna," Carbon copy, November 1966. (Box-folder 44: 18)
  - "The Arabs Have a Case too," Typescript, handwritten notes, and research material, c. 1967. (Box-folder 44: 19)
  - "Arab Night in New York City," Carbon copy, 1967. (Box-folder 44: 20)
  - "J'accuse: An Open Letter to the American Friends of the Middle East," (originally drafted in Spring 1965). Typescript, 14 March 1967 (Box-folder 44: 21)
  - "The Middle East: Another Vietnam?" Speech, Youngstown University, Youngstown, Ohio. Clipping, 15 May 1967. (Box-folder 44: 22)
  - "The Middle East: Another Vietnam?" Speech, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Correspondence, 16 May 1967. (Box-folder 45: 1)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, (date written). Carbon copy, 24 June 1967 (Box-folder 45: 2)
  - "J'accuse: A Memorandum," (regarding Arab public relations and the Arab-American Association for Commerce and Industry). Typescript, c. July 1967 (Box-folder 45: 3)
  - Letter to the editor, Washington Star, (date written). Carbon copy, 6 July 1967 (Box-folder 45: 4)
  - "Memorandum re Public Relations," Photocopy, 7 July 1967. (Box-folder 45: 5)
  - "Where Goes the Middle East?" Speech, Bradford Junior College, Bradford, Massachusetts. Printed copy and notes, 6 October 1967. (Box-folder 45: 6)
  - "The Middle East: Modern Political, Economic, Religious and Ethnic Conflicts," Speech, Flint Junior College, Flint, Michigan. Correspondence, press releases, notes, and clippings, 15 November 1967. (Box-folder 45: 7)
  - "The Arab Refugee Problem," Speech, Kiwanis Club, Flint, Michigan. Clipping and article on Palestinian refugees, 16 November 1967. (Box-folder 45: 8)
  - "The Turbulent Middle East," Film lecture, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana. Correspondence and press release, 20 November 1967. (Box-folder 45: 9)
  - "Where Goes the Middle East?" Speech, Federation of Arab-American Organizations Dinner, Pick-Congress Hotel, Chicago, Illinois. Correspondence, 26 November 1967. (Box-folder 45: 10)
  - Letter to the editor, (date written). Carbon copy, 28 November 1967 (Box-folder 45: 11)
  - "The Turbulent Middle East," Film lecture, Choate School, Wallingford, Connecticut. Mimeographed account, 11 December 1967. (Box-folder 45: 12)
  - "The Independent Order of B'nai B'rith," Typescript and handwritten draft and notes, 1968. (Box-folder 45: 13)
  - "This We Do Believe: If this Be Anti-Semitism, then Make the Most of It," Typescript copy of a seven point Middle East program put out by the Organization Committee of the Americans for Justice and Security in the Middle East, and draft dated 22 December 1967, January 1968. (Box-folder 45: 14)
  - Speech, Women's Club, Town Hall, Oklahoma City, Oklahoma, Press release, 15 February 1968. (Box-folder 45: 15)
  - Speeches, McNeese College, Lake Charles, Louisiana, Clipping, 19-20 February 1968. (Box-folder 45: 16)
  - "The Other Side of the Arab-Israeli Conflict," Speech, University of Colorado, Boulder, Colorado. Clippings and correspondence, 21 February 1968. (Box-folder 45: 17)
  - "What Price Israel?" Speech, University of Utah, Salt Lake City, Utah. Clipping, 26 February 1968. (Box-folder 45: 18)
  - "Where Goes the Middle East?" Speech, Claremont Graduate School and University Center, Claremont, California. Handwritten notes and typescript introduction by William H. Brownlee, as well as correspondence with William H. Brownlee, 6 March 1968. (Box-folder 45: 19)
  - "The Middle East: Friend or Foe?" Speech, Freedom Club, First Congregational Church, Los Angeles, California. Correspondence with Ed Delaney, 11 March 1968. (Box-folder 45: 20)